(波兰  1944年)
(纽约  韦斯切斯特富人区  1944年)
Mother, what are you...
妈妈  你在干嘛...
I thought you were a burglar.
我还以为是小偷
I didn't mean to scare you, darling,
没想到吓着你了  亲爱的
I was just getting a snack.
我只是拿点吃的
Go back to bed.
去睡吧
What's the matter?
怎么了
Go on, back to bed.
去睡觉
I'll make you hot chocolate.
我给你做杯热巧克力
Who are you?
你是谁
And what have you done with my mother?
你把我妈妈怎么了
My mother has never set foot in this kitchen in her life.
我妈妈从不踏进厨房半步
And she certainly wouldn't get me hot chocolate.
她不可能做热巧克力给我喝
Unless she kept ordering me to do it.
只会指使我来干这些
You're not scared of me?
你不怕我吗
I always believed I couldn't be the only one in the world.
我一直不信我是世上唯一的...
The only person who is...
唯一的...
...different.
与众不同的人
And here you are, Charles Xavier.
现在你来了  我叫查尔斯·泽维尔
Raven.
我叫瑞雯
You're hungry, and alone?
你饿了吗
Take whatever you want.
随便拿着吃吧
We've got lots of food, you don't have to steal.
我们有很多食物  你用不着偷
In fact...
其实...
...you never have to steal again.
...你以后再也不用偷了
Understand this, Erik.
你要明白  埃里克
These Nazi's, I'm not like them.
我不像这些纳粹
Genes are the key, yes...
基因是关键
But their goals?
但它们能决定什么呢
Blue eyes, Blond hair, Pathetic.
金发碧眼吗  那就太可悲了
Eat the chocolate.
吃点巧克力吧
It's good.
味道很好
Want some?
来点吗
I want to see my Mama.
我想见我妈
Genes are the keys that unlocks the door to a new age, Erik.
基因是开启新世纪大门的钥匙  埃里克
A new future for mankind.
人类的一个新未来
Evolution.
进化
You know what I'm talking about?
你知道我在说什么吗
It's a simple thing I ask of you.
我要你做的事很简单
A little coin is nothing compared to a big gate.
这枚硬币比那扇大门容易多了
Is it?
是吗
I tried, Herr Doctor...
我尽力了  博士先生...
I can't... I don't...
我做...做不到...
It's impossible.
不行
The one thing I can say for the Nazi's,
对于纳粹  有一件事我可以肯定
is their methods seem to produce results.
他们采用的方法都很有效
I'm sorry, Erik.
很抱歉  埃里克
Mama!
妈妈
My darling.
亲爱的
How are you?
你还好吗
Here's what we're going to do.
我来说说我们将要做什么
I'm going to count to three...
我数到三...
...and you're going to move the coin.
...你来移动这枚硬币
You don't move the coin, I pull the trigger.
如果你移动不了  我就扣下扳机
Understand?
明白吗
One...
一...
- Mama! - You can do it.
- 妈妈  - 你做得到
Two...
二...
Everything is all right.
没事的
Everything is all right!
Three.
三
Yes, wonderful!
太好了
Excellent!
好极了
Outstanding, Erik!
真棒  埃里克
So we unlock you're gift with anger.
愤怒开启了你的天赋
Anger and pain.
愤怒和痛苦
You and me, we're going to have a lot of fun together.
你和我   我们可以一起共创大业
《X战警：第一战》
(瑞士  日内瓦  1962年)
(英国  牛津大学)
Hetero-chromia.
异色症
A gentlemen would at least offer to buy me a drink first.
作为一名绅士  至少该请我喝杯饮料吧
Newman, a pint of bitter for me
纽曼  我要一品脱苦啤酒
and a brandy for the lady, please.
给这位女士来杯白兰地
- How did you know that? - Lucky guess.
- 你怎么知道我想喝什么  - 侥幸猜中
The name's, Xavier, Charles Xavier.
我叫泽维尔  查尔斯·泽维尔
- How do you do... - Amy.
- 你好...- 我叫艾米
Heterochromia, is reference to your eyes,
异色症  是从你眼睛里看出来的
which I have to say are stunning.
那双眼睛真迷人
One green, one blue. It's a mutation.
一只绿色  一只蓝色  是一种变异
It's a very groovy mutation.
一种绝妙的变异
I have news for you, Amy. You are a mutant.
告诉你  艾米  你是个变种人
First you proposition a girl,
先和姑娘调情
and then you call her deformed.
接着叫她怪胎
How is that seduction tactic working for you?
这就是你勾引姑娘的策略吗
I'll tell you in the morning.
明早再告诉你
No, no.
好了  好了
Seriously, you must knock it.
不开玩笑了  你肯定不信
Mutation's go from single cell organisms
变异是单细胞生物
to being the dominate form of reproductive life.
进化成占主导地位的生命体的过程
On this planet,
在这星球上
infinite forms of variations with each generation
每一代生物的进化
all through mutation.
都由变异引起
Then let's reclaim that word.
那我们换个词吧
- Mutant, and proud. - Chin, chin, hey.
- 突变  自豪  - 干杯
Hi, I guess I have to buy my own drink.
看来我得自己买饮料了
I'm sorry, one cola.
很抱歉  来杯可乐
Charles here was just telling me
查尔斯只是想告诉我
that I'm like one of the first sea creatures...
我就像个第一批长出腿的...
that grew legs.
海洋生物
Tiny bit sexier.
有点性感
I'm sorry, this is my sister, Raven.
抱歉  这位是我的妹妹  瑞雯
- Hi, Amy. - And what do you study?
- 你好  艾米  - 你学什么的
Waitressing.
服务员
Oh look, you have hetero-chromia too!
看  你也有异色症
- Say, what? - Look at her eye...
- 什么  - 看她的眼睛...
Right, Raven get your coat please.
好吧  瑞雯拿上你的外套
Don't talk to me, you did that on purpose.
别和我说你是故意的
- I did not! - Yes you did!
- 我不是  - 你是故意的
Why would I do it on purpose?
为什么我要故意那样干
You know I can't control it sometimes.
你知道我有时候也控制不了
When I'm stressed or tired..
压力大了或累了的时候...
You seem to be doing a perfectly good job right now.
刚才你的变形真是天衣无缝
"Mutant and proud"
突变  自豪
Why is it always the pretty mutations,
为什么变种人也会很漂亮
or the invisible ones like yours.
或是像你这样  长相平常
If you're a freak, better hide.
如果你是个怪胎  最好躲起来
You're being ridiculous!
真是太荒谬了
Look, I don't mean to sound like an old fart.
听着  我不想像个老古板一样说话
Which you are.
你就是个老古板
Sometimes, but we've talked about this, Raven.
有时会  但我们聊过这问题  瑞雯
A small slip up is one thing.
小失误在所难免
A big one does not bear thinking about.
犯大错就不堪设想了
"Mutant and proud"
突变  自豪
"Mutant and proud"?
If only...
如果只是...
- Would you date me? - Of course I would.
- 你会和我约会吗  - 当然会
Any man would be lucky to have you.
男人拥有了你  都会觉得很幸运
- You're stunning! - Looking like this?
- 你很漂亮  - 就像这样吗
Like, you...what?
像  什么
Blue?
蓝色
- You're my oldest friend. - I'm your only friend.
- 你是我老朋友  - 也是你唯一的朋友
Thank you for that.
真是荣幸之至
Well?
那么?
I'm incapable of even thinking of you like that,
你这样我想都不会想
I feel responsible for you.
我觉得要对你负责
Anything else would just feel wrong.
其他想法都是错的
But what if you didn't know me?
但如果你不了解我呢
Unfortunately I do know you.
但我很了解你
I don't know what's got into you lately?
你最近怎么了
You're awfully concerned with your looks.
特别在乎自己的容貌
I'm sleepy. Will you read to me?
我要睡了  给我读点东西好吗
I can't, I have my thesis coming up, I have to study.
不行  我的论文快交了  我得学习
Well fine, read about your thesis
好吧  就读你的论文吧
it always sends me right off.
那样睡着得快
To Homo neanderthalensis, his mutant cousin Homo sapiens,
对于尼安德特智人来说  他的突变远亲智人
was an aberration.
是一种畸变
Peaceful co-habitation, if ever it existed,
如果他们曾和平共处过的话
was short lived.
也很短暂
Records show, without exception
据史料记载  在任何地区
that the arrival of the mutated human species
突变人种的到来
in any region was followed by
将导致
the immediate extinction of their less evolved kin.
进化慢的同类立即灭绝   无一例外
Possession of that gold is illegal.
保存这样的黄金是非法的
- I should inform the police. - Let's not play this game.
- 我该通知警察  - 我们别兜圈子了
- Where did you get it? - A Friend.
- 你从哪里得到了这东西  - 朋友那里
He recommended your bank, most highly.
他竭力推荐你们银行
I see.
我明白了
Do you know our terms, sir?
你了解我们的条款吗  先生
Yes.
了解
And you should know mine.
你也该了解我的
This gold is what remains of my people.
这块金砖是我的人民的遗物
Melted from their possessions. Torn from their teeth.
融合他们的财物  撬下他们的金牙
This is blood money.
这是血腥钱
And you're going to help me find
你要帮我找出
the bastards responsible for it.
幕后元凶
Don't touch that alarm.
别碰警铃
I want Schmidt, Klaus Schmidt.
我要找施密特  克劳斯·施密特
Where is he?
他在哪里
Our clients don't supply addresses, we're not...
我们的客户不提供住址  我们不...
Not that sort of bank?
不是那种银行吗
Metal fillings, eh, not gold.
金属填料  不是金的
Worried someone might steal them?
担心被人偷吗
Argentina! Schmidt is in Argentina!
阿根廷  施密特在阿根廷
Villa Gesell! Please, please!
维拉格塞尔酒店  求你了  别
Thank you.
谢谢
I would love to kill you.
我很想杀了你
So mark my words, if you warn anyone, I'm coming...
记住我的话  如果你警告别人  我就会...
...I will find you.
...找到你
(内华达州  拉斯维加斯)
Another day at the office.
又忙活了一天
Is that Colonel Hendry?
那是亨得利上校吗
- The NATO guy? - Yeah.
- 北约的吗  - 对
Yes, it is.
就是他
Cause that's three mob bosses,
因为那儿还有三个大人物
the Italian ambassador, the CEO of Lockheed.
意大利大使  还有洛克希德的首席执行官
They can't all be communists.
他们不可能都是共产党
This Hellfire club's gotta be something else.
这个地狱火俱乐部里肯定另有阴谋
Do you see that? Hello, girls!
看到了吗  有美女
Wow, very nice.
太棒了
Wha...what are you doing?
你在干嘛
Here's things that the CIA didn't give me.
中情局没教过我这样干
Stay put.
在这等我
- Colonel Hendry? - Yes, ma'am.
- 亨得利上校吗  - 是的  夫人
Emma Frost, Sebastian Shaw's associate.
我是艾玛·弗罗斯特  塞巴斯汀·尚的合伙人
And where is, Mr. Shaw?
尚先生呢
We're having a party, and here's the entertainment.
我们正在办派对  我带来点娱乐节目
Come with me.
跟我来
Hello beautiful, how are you?
美人  你好吗
Hey baby, you want to find a quiet place?
小宝贝  想到个安静的地方吗
I am so sorry. I've been booked by Colonel Hendry.
很抱歉  亨得利上校已经预定我了
Excuse me.
借过
- Are you sure we can't get a refill, Bob? - No.
- 不再喝一杯吗  鲍伯  - 不了
So, I hear you blocked
听说你阻止了
the proposal to position Jupiter missiles in Turkey.
在土耳其部署朱庇特导弹的提案
I expect you to reconsider.
希望你可以重新考虑一下
We've had this conversation.
这事我们已经讨论过了
You put our nukes in Turkey,
在土耳其部署核武器
or anywhere that close to Russia,
或任何靠近俄罗斯的地方
and you're looking at war. Nuclear war.
就是挑起战争  核战争
I didn't ask for favors, Colonel.
我不是在请求帮助  上校
I express my expectations.
我在表达我的期望
So, let me say it again.
那我再说一遍
I expect you'll reconsider.
希望你可以再考虑一下
The only thing I will reconsider,
只有一件事我会重新考虑
is having another glass of that delicious champagne.
那就是再来一杯香醇的香槟
What the hell did you put in my drink?
你在我酒里放了什么
You're thinking of running, hiding?
还以为你能跑掉  躲起来吗
We'd find you, Hendry.
我们找得到你  亨得利
There's not a fortress in the world that can keep us out.
世上没有一个堡垒我们进不去
Magnificent, isn't she, Bob?
她很耀眼吧  鲍伯
Genetic mutation, the evolution of the human genome.
基因变异  人类基因的进化
Where's Azazel?
阿撒佐恶魔在哪里
Ah, we don't want the Colonel to be late.
别让上校迟到了
Come here.
来吧
Missiles in Turkey send a very clear message.
在土耳其部署导弹  会传达一个很明确的信息
We ever decided to fire them,
我们可以随时发射
the Russians early warning system
苏联的预警系统
won't even have time to kick in.
还没来得及启用
This better be important, MacTaggert
你说的最好很重要  麦克塔哥特
Whoa, whoa, whoa, slow down.
慢点说
You smoking them funny cigarettes?
你抽了什么  晕了吗
People don't disappear.
人是不会凭空消失的
Colonel Hendry was there.
亨得利上校也在那里
He was there, McCone, in the Hellfire club.
他刚才也在  麦克尼  在地狱火俱乐部
Colonel Hendry?
亨得利上校
I agree with you, General. I've reconsidered my position.
我同意  将军  我重新考虑了我的立场
And I now believe that we should put Jupiter Missiles in Turkey.
现在我觉得应该在土耳其部署导弹
Colonel Hendry is here.
亨得利上校在这里
So, unless he magically traveled
除非在刚才十分钟里
3,000 miles in the last ten minutes,
他魔术般地穿越了三千英里
Listen to me, I suggest that you stop wasting my time.
听着  你就别再浪费我时间了
Looks like Hendry wants to start World War III.
看起来亨得利想发动第三次世界大战
I have better things to deal with right now, MacTaggert.
现在我要处理很多要事  麦克塔哥特
Sir, I...
长官  我...
Have you lost your mind?
你疯了吗
So, now what?
现在怎么办
We find an expert on Genetic Mutation.
我们去找个基因变异的专家
Professor of genetics, Charles Francis Xavier.
遗传学教授  查尔斯·弗朗西斯·泽维尔
So, how does it feel to be a professor?
做教授的感觉怎么样
Well, ah, don't call me that.
别那样叫我
You don't get to be called a Professor
除非有课可上
until you actually have a teaching position.
我不喜欢被称作教授
I know, but it suits you.
我知道  但这和你很相称
No,  don't say that, do say "Lets go have a drink".
别那样说  应该说  我们去喝一杯吧
- Let's go have a drink. - Wonderful!
- 我们去喝一杯吧  - 太棒了
(阿根廷  维拉格塞尔酒店)
- Good evening, my friends! - Good evening!
- 晚上好  朋友们  - 晚上好
- Hot, no? - Yes...
- 天真热  - 是啊
One beer, please.
请来杯啤酒
(卡斯珀蒂娜号  迈阿密)
- German beer? - Of course.
- 德国啤酒吗  - 当然
Yes, it's Bitburger. You like it?
这是碧特博格啤酒  你喜欢吗
The best.
最好的啤酒
What brings you to Argentina?
你们怎么会来阿根廷的
The climate, I'm a pig farmer.
这里的气候不错   我是养猪的
Tailor, since I was a boy.
我从小是个裁缝
My father made the finest suits in Dusseldorf.
我父亲是杜塞尔多夫最好的裁缝
My Parents were from, Dusseldorf.
我父母也来自杜塞尔多夫
- What was their name? - They didn't have a name.
- 他们叫什么  - 他们没名字
It was taken away from them...
他们的名字被人夺走了
...by pig farmers...
...被养猪的
...and tailors.
...被裁缝
"Blood and Honor".
血统与荣誉
Which would you care to shed first?
你喜欢哪个呢
- We were under orders. - Blood then.
- 我们只是听命行事  - 那就流血吧
- Freeze, asshole! - Come on, shoot!
- 别动  混蛋  - 快开枪啊
Who, what are you?
你是谁  还是什么东西
Let's just say I'm Frankenstein's monster.
就把我当成"科学怪人"吧
I'm looking for my creator.
我在寻找我的造物主
Drink, drink, drink!
喝  喝  喝
Oh,  I'm so proud of you.
真为你感到骄傲
I need another drink,and you need another cola
我得再来一瓶啤酒 你得再来瓶可乐
- Congratulations, Professor! - Thank you very much,
- 恭喜你  教授  - 非常感谢
it's much harder than it looks, actually.
实际上比看起来的难多了
No, on your presentation.
不  我是说你的演讲很成功
You knew my presentation?
你听过我的演讲吗
How nice of you, thank you very much.
真好  非常感谢
Moira MacTaggert.
我叫莫伊洛·麦克塔哥特
Charles Xavier.
我是查尔斯·泽维尔
Do you have a minute?
可以聊一会儿吗
For a pretty little beam with a mutated MCR-1 gene,  I have five.
为了漂亮的变异Mcr-1基因  可以聊五分钟
I say, MCR-1, you would say, golden hair.
我说的Mcr-1  就是你们说的金发
It's a mutation, it's a very groovy mutation.
这是种变异  一种绝妙的变异
Mutation you know, took us from single cell organisms,
变异就是  把我们从单细胞生物
to the dominate form...
变成了占主导地位的人类...
You know what, this routine may go over great with the co-eds,
这一套可能对女学生很有吸引力
but I'm here on business.
但我是为了公事而来
What?
什么
I really need your help.
我需要你的帮助
All right.
好吧
The kind that of mutations
在你论文中
that you were talking about in your thesis
谈到过的那种变异
I need to know if they may already have happened.
我想知道那是否已经发生了
In people alive today.
当今世上是否已存在变种人
Professor?
教授
I think that we should just talk when you're sober.
我看还是等你清醒了再谈吧
Do you have any time tomorrow?
你明天有时间吗
Something tells me,
我觉得
you already know the answer to your question.
你已经找到了问题的答案
This is very important to me.
这对我也很重要
And if I can help you, I will do my utmost.
我会尽最大努力帮你
Thank you.
谢谢
(佛罗里达州  迈阿密)
Still drinking champagne, Bob?
还喝香槟吗  鲍伯
I will pass.
不喝了
Okay, well so much for the pleasantries.
好了  不开玩笑了
I was wondering, who you told about our little arrangement?
你把我们的计划告诉谁了
No one.
没人
He's telling the truth.
他说的是事实
Good.
很好
Well I guess we're done here.
那这儿就没什么事了
Let's wrap things up, shall we?
我们收拾东西走人怎么样
Well I knew better than to trust you.
我不至于笨得相信你
Now you let me walk out of here with my money.
你现在   给我钱放我走
Or I will pull this pin and we all die.
否则我就拉开拉环  我们同归于尽
Go ahead, pull it.
行啊  拉吧
I'll do it, I swear to god.
我会的  对天发誓
No you won't.
不  你不会
But I will.
但是我会
You're one of them?
你也是变种人
Very astute of you, Colonel Hendry.
聪明  亨得利上校
You want to guess what I can do?
猜猜看我能做什么
I've got the power to absorb energy.
我能吸收能量
It keeps me young.
这让我保持年轻
That's the boring part.
这没什么意思
The fun stuff is what I can do with it once I got it.
有意思的是我能利用吸收的能量
(弗吉尼亚  兰利  中央情报局总部)
The advent of the nuclear age,
核时代的到来
may have accelerated the mutation process.
可能会加速基因变异的进程
Individual's with extraordinary abilities may already be among us.
拥有超能力的人或许就在我们之间
Thank you very much.
谢谢大家
MacTaggert, you really think that
麦克塔哥特  你真的觉得
some crackpot scientist is going to make me believe in
这个胡扯的科学家会让我相信
sparkly dames and vanishing men?
银光闪闪的女人和瞬移男人的存在吗
You just brought yourself a one way
你是给自己找了一条路
ticket back to the typing pool.
回到原来的打字小组去吧
This meeting is over.
会议结束
Uh, please sit down agent, MacTaggert.
请先坐下  麦克塔哥特特工
I didn't really expect you to believe me.
我不指望你们相信我
Given that all you could think about
考虑到你们在我做陈述的时候
during my presentation, was what sort of pie
满脑子想的都是今天食堂里
they were serving in the commissary.
提供的到底是哪种馅饼
It's apple pecan.
是苹果山核桃馅饼
I haven't been entirely honest with you, and I'm sorry.
我没有对你完全坦诚  我很抱歉
You see, one of the many spectacular things my mutation allows me to do,
我所拥有的超能力之一就是
is that I can read your mind.
我能知道你在想什么
I've seen this before in a magic show.
我看过那个魔术
Are you going to ask us to
你现在是不是要让我们
think of a number between one and ten now?
在一到十之间想一个数字
No, agent Stryker.
不  斯特瑞克特工
Although I could ask you about your son William
虽然我会问你刚才想的
who you were thinking about,
儿子威廉的事
which is very nice.
这样也不错
But I think I'd rather ask you about
但我还是更想问你有关
the Jupiter missiles America are currently placing in Turkey.
美国正在土耳其部署朱比特中程导弹的事情
He's a goddamn spy!
他是个该死的间谍
You brought a goddamn spy!
你竟然带来了一个间谍
I did not, I would never bring one here!
我没有  我不可能带间谍来这里
How's that for a magic trick?
这个魔术怎么样
Best I've ever seen.
无与伦比
I want them out of here.
我希望他们离开这里
And lock down until I can figure out what to do.
关好他们  直到我想出对策
My facility is off site. I'll take them.
我带他们去我的基金吧
I can't believe this.
真叫人难以相信
You'd think the director of the CIA would have a little more composure.
你还以为中情局首脑能冷静一点
We should be going after Shaw right now,
我们现在应该追查尚
but instead he's up there worrying about the wrong mutants.
他却在担心其他变种人
What are we doing to do, Lavene?
我们该怎么办  雷维
Lavene? Lavene, what's wrong with you?
雷维  雷维  你怎么了
Absolutely nothing,
他没怎么
I've just frozen him for the moment because I'd like to talk to you.
我只是暂时将他定住  我想和你谈话
It's good, isn't it?
这很好  不是吗
I'm as interested in this Sebastian Shaw as you are,
我和你一样对塞巴斯汀·尚很感兴趣
And if you still want my help,
如果你还需要我的帮助
meet me on the third floor of the parking garage.
就到三楼的停车库来见我
I've always known that there were people like you out there.
我一直相信你们这种人的存在
I've been the laughing stock of this agency for years
虽然这一直被大家当成笑柄
but I knew it.
但是我相信这是真的
You're going to love my facility.
你会喜欢我的基地
That's going to have to wait.
那必须得等会儿
Why?
为什么
Agent MacTaggert has to lead us to Sebastian Shaw,
麦克塔哥特要带我们去见塞巴斯汀·尚
and if we don't move now apparently we're going to loose him.
现在不去  他就要溜了
What?
什么
Not only can he read minds,
他不仅仅可以读心
he can communicate with them as well.
也可以和他们交流
Moria and I have just had a lovely conversation.
我和莫伊洛刚刚聊得不错
Yes, we did.
是啊没错
That is incredible!
真难以置信
But I cannot take you anywhere else,
但是没有上级的许可
without permission from upstairs.
我不能带你们去别的地方
Would you like to see one more magic trick?
你还想看魔术吗
Okay.
想
Get in the car.
那就上车
Good idea.
好主意
Herr Doctor.
你好医生
Little Erik Lensherr.
小埃里克·勒舍尔
He's here to kill you.
他是来杀你的
What kind of greeting is that?
这是哪门子的待客之道
After all these years?
过了这么多年
Emma.
艾玛
We don't harm our own kind.
我们不该伤害我们的同类
Ah, now it's a party.
现在才是真正的派对
This is the US Coast guard.
这里是美国海岸警卫队
Do not attempt to move your vessel.
不许移动你们的船只
Stay where you are.
留在原地
They have a telepath.
他们有人会心灵感应
I've lost, Shaw!
我感应不到尚了
I've lost, I've lost, Shaw.
感应断了  断了  尚
There's, there's something blocking me.
有...有人阻碍我
This has never happened to me before.
这之前从来没有发生过
I think there's someone like me on that ship.
那艘船上有和我一样的人
Like you?
和你一样
I'm sorry, a telepath.
抱歉  是心灵感应
This is incredible,
真不可思议
I can actually feel her inside my mind.
我可以感受到她
I'm very sorry,
我很抱歉
but I don't think I'm going to be much help to you tonight.
估计今晚我可能帮不了什么忙了
You're on your own.
靠你们自己了
- Oh my god. - Jesus.
- 天哪  - 上帝啊
Get inside.
到里面去
Stop, stop, stop!
停下  停下  停下
Charles! You okay?
查尔斯  你还好吗
There's someone else out there.
还有人在外面
There!
那儿
Time to go.
是时候该走了
Let go!
放手
Better let it go!
放手吧
You've got help him...
你得帮他
there's someone in the water, help him!
有人在水里  救救他
Let it go! You have to let it go!
放手吧  你必须得放手
You can't, you'll drown. You have to let go.
住手  你会淹死的  你必须放手
I know what this means to you but you're going to die.
我知道这对你很重要  但是你会死的
Please, Erik, calm your mind.
拜托了  埃里克  冷静
Get off of me, get off!
放开我  放开
- Calm down, please. - We're here!
- 冷静  拜托  - 我们在这
Who are you?
你是谁
Professor Charles Xavier.
查尔斯·泽维尔教授
You were in my head.
你侵入我的思想
How did you do that?
你怎么做到的
You have your tricks, I have mine.
你有超能力  我也有
I'm like you, just calm your mind.
我和你一样  请冷静
- I thought I was alone. - You're not alone.
- 我以为我是孤身一人  - 你不是一个人
Erik, you're not alone.
埃里克  你不是一个人
(中央情报局秘密研发基地)
Welcome to my facility.
欢迎来到我的基地
My mission has been to investigate the application
我的职责是研究
of paranormal powers for military defense.
用于军事防御或是进攻的
Or offense.
超能力
This guy, Shaw, Schmidt,
这个家伙  尚  施密特
whatever you want to call him.
不管你们怎么称呼他
He's working with the Russians.
他和苏联人一起工作
We might need your help to stop them.
我们需要你们的帮助来阻止他们
Marvelous.
太好了
So we're to be the CIA's new mutant division, yes?
所以我们现在是中情局的变种人部门吗
Something like that.
差不多吧
It's a supersonic. The most advanced plane ever built.
这是超音速飞机  是目前最先进的飞机
You should see it in real life.
你们该见识下它的用途
It's incredible.
太不可思议了
Hank, these are the special new recruits I was telling you about.
汉克  这些是我和你提过的特殊的新员工
This is, Hank McCoy,
这是汉克·麦考伊
one of our most talented young researchers.
最出色的青年研究员之一
How wonderful, another mutant. Already here.
原来这已经有一个厉害的变种人
Why didn't you say?
你为什么不说
Say what?
说什么
Because you don't know.
原来你不知道
I am so, so terribly sorry!
我感到非常非常抱歉
Hank?
汉克
You didn't ask, so I didn't tell.
你没问  所以我也没说
So your mutation's what? You're super smart?
所以你的超能力是什么  智商超群吗
I'll say, Hank here graduated honors
我来说吧  汉克在十五岁的时候
at the age of fifteen.
就以优异的成绩毕业了
I wish that's all it was.
我真希望只是这样
You're among friends now, Hank.
我们是你的朋友  汉克
You could show off.
你可以展现自己的能力
Splendid.
真是厉害
- Sorry. - Yes, yes.
- 借过  - 没事
You're amazing.
你很厉害
Really?
真的吗
The presence of U.S. Missiles in Turkey
今天苏联外交部长基米柯先生提出警告
represents an unprecedented threat to the people of the Soviet Union.
美国在土耳其部署导弹
Warned Russian Mister Gromeko, earlier today
对苏联人民来说意味着空前的威胁
But he was quick to insist
但他同时强调
the Russians would not be the first to initiate any military action.
苏联不会最先采取军事行动
Yeah, we'll fix that as soon as we get to Russia.
等我们一到苏联  就能搞定一切
Unless the CIA finds us first.
除非中情局在那之前先找到我们
I'll take care of them too.
我也会留心他们的
If that telepath gets inside your head,
如果那心灵感应潜入你的思想
he won't be as much fun as I am.
他可不会像我这样有趣
Already in hand, my love.
已经在我掌控之中了  亲爱的
The Russians made me this.
那些苏联人给我造了这个
So, what am I thinking?
现在  我在想什么
I don't know.
我不知道
I was thinking that
我在想
you are the  most exquisite thing that I've ever seen in my life.
你是我一生中见过的最美的女人
And that this needs ice.
还有这里需要加点冰
Fetch me some.
给我来点
There's a good girl.
真是好姑娘
I, I promised myself I'd find a cure,
自从我懂事起
ever since I was a little boy.
我就发誓要找到治疗的方法
You have no idea what I'd give to feel...
你不能明白我希望变得...
- normal. - Normal.
- 普通  - 普通
Charles has never understood.
查尔斯不会明白
He's different, but he's never had to hide.
他异于常人  但他不需要隐藏
Hank，this serum that you're making,
汉克  你所制的那些血清
it doesn't affect abilities, right?
不会影响超能力对吗
Just appearance. Normalizes it.
只是让外表正常
Yeah.
是的
Do you think it would work on me?
你觉得这对我有用吗
I can look into it, if you'd like.
如果你喜欢  我可以继续研究
That's the least I can do after asking
让你来听了这个奇怪的请求之后
you to come down here to listen to a weird request.
起码我可以为你做这件事
I have to admit,
我必须得承认
usually when guys ask me out they're not after my blood.
通常男生约我可不会是想抽我的血
S..sorry, I didn't intend to be forward.
对不起  我不是有意冒犯
I was just...I was excited.
我只是...很激动
You know, the nature of your mutation.
你变异的类型
If any genes hold the key to changing appearance, it's yours.
你的基因可以改变外表
Hank, you aren't being forward,
汉克  你没有冒犯
that's kinda what I meant.
虽然我之前确实有点觉得
No, but I'm just sorry if you thought I was.
如果你之前这么认为我很抱歉
And I'm sorry that you weren't.
很抱歉误会你了
Go ahead, take the blood.
来吧  抽血吧
Sorry, did I hurt you?
对不起  我伤到你了吗
Kinky!
真亲昵啊
By the way,
话说
if I looked like you, I wouldn't change a thing.
如果我像你那样  我不会改变自己
(塞巴斯汀·尚  118470号档案)
What I know about you,
以我对你的了解
I'm surprised you managed to stay this long.
你这么快就走实在让我惊讶
- What do you know about me? - Everything.
- 你了解我什么  - 所有的一切
Then know to stay out of my head.
那就别侵入我的思想
I'm sorry Erik,
我很抱歉  埃里克
but I've seen what Shaw did to you.
但是我看到了尚对你做的事情
I felt your agony.
我感受到你的痛苦
I can help you.
我可以帮你
I don't need your help.
我不需要你的帮助
Don't kid yourself. You needed my help last night.
别自欺欺人了  昨晚你就需要我的帮忙
It's not just me you're walking away from.
如果没有我你不会安然脱身的
Here you have the chance
现在你有机会
to be a part of something much bigger than yourself.
成为比现在强大许多的你
I won't stop you leaving,
我不会阻止你的离开
I could.
我可以
But I won't.
但是我不会
Shaw's got friends.
尚有朋友
You could do with some.
你也可以有
Hank turned that radar installation into a transmitter.
汉克把这个雷达装置改装成了一台发射机
It's designed to amplify brain waves,
可以增强脑电波
so it could enhance your telepathic powers.
以此来增强你的心灵感应能力
Help us find other mutants for our division.
帮助我们找到更多的变种人
I thought they'd all been found by you.
我还以为他们都被你找到了
Erik!
埃里克
You decided to stay.
你决定留下来了
If a new species is being discovered,
如果有新的物种
it should be by its own kind.
它应该是被自己的同类发现
Charles and I find the new mutants, no suits.
查尔斯和我来找新变种人  而不是你们
First of all, that's my machine out there.
首先  那是我的机器
Second of all, and much more importantly,
第二  也是更重要的
this is Charles decision.
这是查尔斯的决定
Charles is fine with the CIA being involved. Isn't that right?
查尔斯不介意中情局的参与  不是吗
No, I'm sorry but, I'm with Erik.
不  很抱歉  但是  我同意埃里克
We'll find them alone.
该由我们自己来发现他们
What if I say no?
如果我不答应呢
Then good luck using your installation
那就祝你在没有我的情况下
without me.
好好利用这个装置
I call it, Cerebro.
我叫它Cerebro
- Isn't that Spanish for "Brain"? - Yes.
- 这是"大脑"的西班牙语说法吗  - 是的
Okay so, the electrodes
好的  这些电极
connect Charles to the transmitter on the roof.
连接查尔斯和屋顶上的发射机
And picks up a mutant.
如果找到变种人
His brain sends a signal through a relay.
他的大脑会通过感应器发出信号
And then the co-ordinates of their location are printed out here.
然后他们所在的地理坐标就会在这显示出来
You designed this?
你设计的吗
Yeah.
是的
What an adorable lab rat you make, Charles.
你这样子真像个可爱的实验鼠啊  查尔斯
Don't spoil this for me, Erik.
别损我了  埃里克
I've been a lab rat,
我曾经也是实验室里的小白鼠
I know one when I see one.
所以我能认出来
Okay, right
好了  很好
Are you sure we can't shave your head?
你确定不剃头吗
Don't touch my hair.
别想碰我的头发
It's working!
成功了
With that Daddy-O,
有票子  大帅哥
you get a private dance.
你可以到包间里享受私人舞蹈
You cat's know it's double for both, right?
你们应该知道双人是要付两倍的钱吧
No, that won't be necessary. Although I sure we...
那不重要  虽然我...
We were thinking more,
我们想看得更多
we're show you ours,
如果你秀你的表演
...if you show us yours.
我们就秀我们的表演
Baby, that is not the way it works around here.
宝贝  这可不是这里的规矩
- More tea, Vicar? - Don't mind if I do.
- 要来点吗  - 乐意之至
My turn.
该我了
How would you like a job,
给你个不脱衣服的活儿
where you get to keep your clothes on?
你觉得怎么样
- Where to fellas? - Richmond, Virginia.
- 要去哪儿  小伙子们  - 弗吉尼亚  里士满
Right, so you want the airport,
好  这么说你们是要去机场
the station, what?
火车站还是哪里
No we were rather hoping that you would take us all the way.
不  其实我们希望你能带我们回去
That's a six hour drive.
那可要六小时车程
That will give us plenty of time to talk.
那样我们才有足够的时间来聊天
What the hell does the government want with
政府到底想要
a guy like, Alex Summers?
阿历克斯·萨默斯这样的人做什么
I hope you don't plan on putting him with others.
我劝你们别试图把他和别人放在一起
First guy I ever met who actually prefers solitary confinement.
这是我遇到的第一个宁愿要单独监禁的人
- Crazy, huh? - What?
- 很神奇是吧  - 什么
You like fish, I like fish too.
你喜欢鱼  我也喜欢鱼
Maybe we should bide some time and talk about it.
也许我们该找个时间出去好好聊聊
I'd rather go out with the fish.
我宁愿和鱼约会
These fish?
你指它们
- Excuse me I'm Erik Lensher. - Charles Xavier.
- 打扰了  我是埃里克·勒舍尔  - 我是查尔斯·泽维尔
Go fuck yourselves.
滚你妈的
- There's nothing on radar? - No.
- 雷达上什么也没发现  - 是的
- Sonar? - No.
- 声纳仪呢  - 也没有
Then we have a problem.
我们有麻烦了
Beautiful, isn't it?
漂亮吧
The reason we exist. We are the children of the atom, my love.
我们存在的原因  我们都是原子的产物  宝贝
We have a situation.
我们有状况了
The telepath...
那个心灵感应者...
I shouldn't be able to feel him at this distance.
这里我本来感觉不到他
It's like his reach is...
好像他的势力范围...
...amplified.
...扩大了
They're recruiting.
他们在招兵买马
You go on to Russia, I'll handle him.
你只管去苏联  我来处理他
I can't stop thinking about the others out there.
我总忍不住去想其他人
All those minds that I've touched.
我能感应到他们所有的想法
I could feel them, their aspirations,
我可以感觉到他们  他们的愿望
their hopes, their ambitions.
他们的理想  他们的野心
I tell you, we've started something incredible, Erik.
埃里克  我们正在做一些难以置信的事情
- We can help them. - Can we?
- 我们能帮助他们  - 能吗
Identification, that's how it starts.
验明身份  那是第一步
Then ends with being rounded up. Experimented on, eliminated.
之后就是集中  测试  淘汰
I know the story.
我知道那些
We have common enemies, Shaw and the Russians they need us.
我们有共同的敌人  对付尚和那些苏联人
For now.
目前看来是的
We should think of code names.
我们得想想代号了
We're government agents now, we should have secret code names.
我们现在是政府特工人员  得有个机密代号
I want to be called, Mystique.
我想叫魔形
Damn, I wanted to be called, Mystique.
不会吧  我还想叫魔形呢
Well tough, I called it.
抱歉了  我定了
Damn wang, mysterious to you.
你还真神秘
Darwin, what about you?
达尔文  你呢
Well, uh, Darwin's already a nickname.
其实达尔文就是个绰号
And you know, sort of fits. Adapt to survive and all.
适应的一种方式而已  适者生存嘛
Check this out.
来看看这个
- Thank you, thank you. - Bravo, bravo.
- 谢谢  - 太棒了
- What about you? - I'm going to be...
- 那你呢  - 我想叫...
Banshee.
海妖
Why do you want to be names after a wailing spirit?
干吗起个代表恐怖哭声的名字
You might want to cover your ears.
你们大概需要捂上耳朵了
Your turn.
轮到你了
My stage name is Angel. Kind of fits.
我的艺名是天使  也是适应生存
- You can fly? - Ah, hah. And uh...
- 你会飞  - 是的  还会这个
- What's your name? - How about Big Foot?
- 你叫什么  - 大脚怎样
Well you know what they say about guys with big feet?
你知道别人怎么说大脚吗
And uh, yours are kind of small.
还有  你的脚够小的了
Okay, now.
那么
Alex, what is your gift? What can you do?
阿历克斯  你的天赋呢  你能做什么
Uh, it's not um, I just can't do it.
我不能表演
- I can't do it in here. - Can you do it out there?
- 不能在这里表演  - 在外面行吗
- Why don't you just do it out there. - Come on. Come on, Alex.
- 去外面不就行了  - 来一个  阿历克斯
Alex! Alex!
阿历克斯! 阿历克斯!
That's the spirit.
这才对
Get down when I tell you.
我说趴下你们就趴下
Get back.
退回去
Get back!
Whatever...
不管你们了...
We've got Intel that Shaw is
我们得到消息称尚准备
meeting with the Russian defense chief in Moscow.
在莫斯科会见苏联国防部长
So go ahead, say it.
继续说吧
I'm not here to say "I told you so",
我可不是来说"早告诉过你"的
you know why I'm here.
你知道我来干吗
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Clearance to bring along your mutants.
是  是  是  清理地方发展你的变种人
Fight fire with fire.
以毒攻毒
Makes sense.
有点意思
Wait, you're okay with this?
等等  你觉得这样好吗
Sending in a bunch of untrained unauthorized freaks?
派遣一帮没训练没授权的怪胎
These "Freaks" are dedicated hard working people.
这些"怪胎"都是辛勤工作的人
Plane leaves for Russia in an hour.
飞机一小时后去苏联
I'm telling you these kids are not ready for, Shaw.
这些孩子们还没准备好对付尚
I think they're going to surprise you.
我想他们会给你惊喜的
They are an exceptional bunch of young people.
他们可不是一般的年轻人
What the hell?
搞什么鬼
Harder!
用力
What are you doing?
你们在干吗
- Who destroyed the statue? - It was, Alex.
- 谁弄坏了雕像  - 阿历克斯干的
No Havok! We have to call him, Havok. That's his name now.
是蹂躏者  他的新名字  蹂躏者
And we were thinking, you should be, Professor X
我们还想  你应该叫X教授
And you should be, Magneto.
你就叫万磁王好了
Exceptional.
真不一般
I expect more from you.
我对你们很失望
(苏联军事避难所)
We got a problem.
有麻烦了
- What? - I'm so sorry, this wasn't on the map.
- 怎么  - 不好意思  地图上没标这个
No matter what happens, act normally.
不管发生什么  自然点
I'll take care of this, all right.
我会处理好的  没事的
Now listen to me..
现在听我的
Where are you going?
你们去哪里
To our farm.
我们的农场
Open the back.
打开车厢
As you wish, as you wish.
好的  好的
Oh, easy, easy. Take it easy, chaps.
放松  放松  伙计们
Anything back there?
后面有什么
Nothing, it's empty.
什么都没  空的
- Everything's okay? - Yes.
- 没有问题了吗  - 是的
- Where's Shaw? - Emma.
- 尚在哪  - 是艾玛
She's a telepath, if I read her, she'll know we're here.
她也是个心灵感应者  我的感应会被她发现
Let me try something else.
我试试别的途径
Shaw sends his apologies, but he's indisposed.
尚让我道歉  他不舒服来不了
He asked me to come in his place.
他让我代替他
But between you and I honey, I'm a lot better company.
不过就我看  我俩会相处更好
Please come in.
进来吧
He's not coming.
他没来
- So, what now boss? - Now, nothing. We're here for Shaw.
- 头儿  现在怎么办  - 什么也不办  我们等的是尚
- Mission aborted. - The hell it is.
- 任务流产  - 狗屁任务
- Erik. - She's his right hand woman.
- 埃里克  - 她是他的得力助手
That's good enough for me.
对我来说已经不错了
The CIA invading the home of a senior Soviet official.
中情特工袭击高级苏联官员的住所
- Are you crazy? - I'm not CIA.
- 你疯了  - 我可不是中情特工
Erik!
埃里克
To your health.
祝你健康
So you must be busy planning your next move.
那么您一定正忙于采取下一步行动
What with the American's
贵国如何应对
refusing to remove their missiles from Turkey.
美国拒绝从土耳其撤出其导弹
You know I can't talk about those things, Miss Frost.
我不能透露这些机密  弗罗斯特小姐
Emma.
叫我艾玛
And don't worry, you don't have to say a word.
别担心  您什么都不用说
He's going to start world war III single handed.
他准备一手策划第三次世界大战吗
- We have to do something. - Like what?
- 我们得做点什么  - 比如说呢
- We're moving out. - You can't.
- 开始行动  - 不行
I'm sorry, I can't leave him.
对不起  我不能让他自己干
For goodness sake, Erik...
看在上帝的份上  埃里克
Be calm.
冷静
Be calm. Forget my face. Yes.
冷静  忘了我  对了
You're beautiful, so beautiful...yes.
你真美  真漂亮
Pathetic.
可怜虫
Nice trick.
好魔术
Who are you?
你们是谁
Go to sleep.
睡觉去
You can stop trying to read my mind, sugar.
别试着读我的思想了
You're never going to get anything from me while I'm like this.
我变成这样的时候你什么也读不出来
So then you can just tell us.
那你就用嘴说吧
Where is Shaw?
尚在哪
Erik.
埃里克
Erik, that's enough.
埃里克  可以了
Erik, that's enough!
All yours.
拿去吧
She won't be shifting into diamond form again.
她变不了钻石体了
But if she does, just give her a gentle tap.
如果还变  敲她一下
(美利坚合众国)
(古巴)
(美国)
(苏联)
We are the children of the atom.
我们都是原子的产物
Radiation gave birth to mutants.
辐射给了变种人生命
What will kill the humans, will only make us stronger.
让人类致命的东西只会让我们更强大
Beautiful, isn't it?
很漂亮  是吗
This is worse that we previously imagined.
比我们预计的更糟
We're taking you with us.
我们带你一起走
- CIA will want to question you themselves. - I doubt it.
- 中情局想亲自问你  - 他们行吗
Might be other things to worry about right now.
或许现在不用担心这个问题
Whoa, all right.
不错哦
Jesus, man you are killing me.
上帝啊  你杀了我
Don't beat yourself up, we got a lot of spare time.
别虐待自己了  我们有大把时间
Oh, I didn't know the circus was in town.
原来马戏团竟然在这里
Hey come on honey, give us a little, uh...
来吧  宝贝  让我们看看
No? Come on, let's see the foot.
来吧  让我们看看你的脚
There it is, come on Bigfoot. let's go.
来吧  来吧  大脚  来一个
Hey, hey come on, hey.
别这样嘛
They're just guys being stupid.
他们只是蠢货而已
Guy's being stupid I can handle. I can handle that my whole life.
我能忍受蠢货  多久都能忍
But I'd rather have a bunch
但是我宁愿有一帮家伙
of guys staring at me with my clothes off,
盯着我脱衣服
then the way these one stare at me.
也不愿意他们像这样看我
At us.
看我们
What was that?
什么状况
I don't know, but something doesn't feel right.
不知道  但是感觉不妙
- No news of Shaw? - Not a peep,
- 还没有尚的消息  - 一点都没
nothing through that back channel.
秘密渠道一点消息都没有
What is that?
怎么回事
We have an intruder on the main atrium.
主厅有入侵者
Where are the mutants?
变种人在哪里
Take another step, I'm going to put you down.
动一动  我就开枪
Of course you will, but where do I find the more evolved people?
你开吧  不过先告诉我去哪找那些高等人类
Send back-up now!
请速支援
Get back, get back, do not leave that room. We're under attack.
退后  退后  待在房里  我们遭到袭击
- Look out! - Shoot it, shoot it!
- 小心  - 开枪  开枪
Where are the mutants?
变种人呢
Put that man down or we will open fire.
把人放下  否则开火
Stay here my ass. Let's go!
待在这里才怪  快跑
- Get back! - We can help, we can help!
- 回去  - 我们能帮忙
Wait, wait, you want the mutants?
等等  你找变种人
They're right through that door.
他们就在那扇门里
Just let us normal people go.
放过我们普通人吧
We're no...
我们不会...
Where's the telepath?
那个心灵感应者呢
- Not here. - Too bad.
- 不在这里  - 真糟
Now I can take this silly thing off.
那我就能把这该死的东西去掉了
Good evening My name is, Sebastian Shaw.
晚上好  我是塞巴斯汀·尚
And I am not here to hurt you.
我不会伤害你们
Freeze!
别动
Azazel...
阿撒佐恶魔
My friends, there's a revolution coming.
伙伴们  革命马上就要开始了
When mankind discovers who we are, what we can do.
当人类发现我们  我们的能力
Each of us will face a choice.
我们都将面对一个选择
Be enslaved, or rise up to rule.
被奴役  还是反过来统治世界
Choose freely, but know that if you are not with us,
随你选  但是如果你不与我们同行
then by definition you are against us.
就意味着和我们为敌
So, you can stay, and
所以  你可以待着不动
fight for the people who hate, and fear you.
为那些憎恶害怕你们的人类而战
Or you can join me. And live like kings.
或者是加入我  如王者般活着
And Queens.
或像王后
- Angel? - Are you kidding me?
- 天使  - 不是开玩笑吧
Come on, we don't belong here.
得了吧  我们不属于这里
And that's nothing to be ashamed of.
没什么好惭愧的
We have to do something.
我们得采取行动了
Stop, I'm coming with you.
等等  我加入
Good choice.
选得好
So tell me about your mutation.
你的变种能力是什么
Well, I adapt to survive.
为生存而适应
- So I guess I'm coming with you. - I like that.
- 我算是加入了吧  - 不错
- Alex, do it! - Get down!
- 阿历克斯  开始  - 趴下
Protecting your fellow, mutants?
保护你的伙伴吗  变种人
It's a noble gesture. Feels good.
姿势挺帅  感觉不错
Adapt to this.
适应这个试试
(苏联  莫斯科)
Hello.
你好
Once again, my sympathies
对于美国中情局所作的一切
for your treatment at the hands of the CIA.
再次对您表示深切的同情
These American's are ruthless.
这些美国人太残忍了
Now they have their missiles placed in Turkey.
现在他们又在土耳其部署导弹
I expect you'll be planning new missile sites of your own.
希望你正在策划的新导弹基地
Somewhere where you know
选在那些
the American early warning system
美国预警系统
won't help.
涉及不到的地方
I hear Cuba is lovely this time of year.
听说古巴这个季节不错
And so close to Florida.
离佛罗里达还挺近
Missiles in Cuba?
在古巴部署导弹
You're serious?
你不是开玩笑吧
We may as well declare war.
那还不如直接宣战呢
Maybe I wasn't clear enough.
可能我没说清楚
You will make this happen.
你会让这些发生的
Okay.
那好吧
Let's see what KGB think about this.
听听克格勃怎么说吧
Hello, General Armivolkoff.
你好  我是沃尔科夫将军
It's nothing.
没事了
Raven.
瑞雯
We've made arrangements for you to be taken home immediately.
我们安排你们立即回家
- We're not going home. - What?
- 我们不回家  - 什么
- He's not going back to prison. - They killed Darwin.
- 他不要回监狱  - 他们杀了达尔文
All the more reason for you to leave.
让你们离开有诸多原因
This is over.
一切都结束了
Darwin is dead, Charles. And we can't even bury him.
达尔文死了  查尔斯  我们甚至没法安葬他
We can avenge him.
我们可以替他报仇
Erik, word please.
埃里克  借一步说话
- They're just kids. - No, they were kids.
- 他们还是孩子  - 不  他们曾是孩子
Shaw has his army, we need ours.
尚有自己的部队  我们也需要
We'll have to train. All of us.
我们需要特训  所有人
- Yes? - Yeah.
- 好吗  - 好的
Well we can't stay here.
我们不能待在这里了
Even if they reopen the department, it's not safe.
哪怕重建也不安全
We've got no where to go.
我们无处可去
Yes, we do.
是的
The law says we've got to turn her over.
依律我们得策反她
The law applies to human beings.
法律是针对人类的
The same laws don't apply to mutants. They're too dangerous.
人类法律约束不了变种人  他们太危险了
Times like this, security is more important than liberty.
非常时期  安全比自由重要的多
- There's a war coming, John. - Yes, but a war with who?
- 战争快爆发了  约翰  - 是啊  和谁打
Excellent question.
问得好
Though I won't call it a war exactly.
虽然我不太确定该不该叫它战争
That suggests both sides stand an equal chance of winning.
因为那个词表明两方势均力敌
Captain, no sign of any American ships.
舰长  没有任何美舰的迹象
Maintain course, full ahead.
保持航线  全速前进
The Russians have sent their warheads to Cuba.
苏联佬已经把弹头拉到古巴了
We have a week before their ship hits the coast.
他们的船还有一周登陆
Our fleet can be on this line,
当苏联佬的船抵达时
when the Russian missile ship arrives.
我们的舰队可以布置在这一线
If that ship crosses the line,
如果他们越过这条线
they will have declared war against the United States.
就是在和美国宣战
We will have no choice but
到时我们就别无选择
to retaliate with a full nuclear response.
只能进行报复性的核回应了
Do we agree?
通过吗
Dispatch the Seventh fleet.
派遣第七舰队
- This is yours? - No, it's ours.
- 这是你的  - 是咱们的
Honestly Charles, I don't know how you survived.
说实在的查尔斯  我不知道你怎么养家糊口的
Living in such hardship.
生活得水深火热
Well it was a hardship softened by me.
那水深火热已经被我缓和了
Come on, time for the tour.
来吧  参观时间
(苏联  莫斯科)
Dear comrades.
亲爱的同志们
The United States
美国政府
have dispatched war ships for Cuba.
已经派遣战舰到古巴
This leaves us with no choice.
这使我们没有退路
Comrade First Secretary.
首席大臣同志
We must send in our fleet.
我们必须派出我们的舰队
Dispatch the fleet!
调遣舰队
President Kennedy has signed a formal proclamation.
肯尼迪总统签署正式公告
Setting up a blockade of all missiles, armed for Cuba.
对古巴进行全面武装封锁
The Soviet Union reacted by terming it
作为回应  苏联提出这一举动
as step along the road to unleashing a thermal nuclear war.
将成为热核战争的导火线
(《纽约论坛报》  核战迫在眉睫)
- You're sure? - I'm sure.
- 真要这么干吗  - 来吧
Hold it.
稳住
No, I can't. I'm sorry.
不行  我做不到  抱歉
I can't shoot anybody point blank,
这么近的距离  我没办法开枪
let alone my friend.
况且还是我的朋友
Oh come on, you know I can deflect it.
怕什么  你知道我能搞定的
You're always telling me I should push myself.
不是你一直叫我对自己狠点儿吗
If you know you can deflect it,
你要是确信搞得定它
then you're not challenging yourself.
就不算自我挑战了
What ever happened to the man
曾经某人想举起潜水艇
who was trying to raise a submarine?
结果怎么样来着
What, I can't.
我移不动它
Something that big, I need the situation, the anger.
它太大  得是怒火中烧我才搞得定
No, the anger isn't enough.
不对  光有怒气可不顶用
It's gotten the job done all this time.
我一直都靠怒气过关斩将
It's nearly gotten you killed all this time.
每次它都让你濒临绝境
Hey, come here.
来这边
Let's try something a little more challenging.
来试点儿更有挑战性的
My step-father took the possibility of nuclear war quite seriously.
我的继父觉得核战一触即发
This way.
走这边
That's why he had this bunker built down here.
所以他在这儿建了地堡
I thought we could use it as a practice range of sort.
我们可以在这里做些训练
You don't think I'm going to blow though the walls?
墙不会被我轰塌了吗
No, he had this place built to with stand a nuclear bomb.
不会  这地方能抵得住核弹
I think it can handle you, Alex.
所以接得住你的招  阿历克斯
You know when I do this, bad things tend to happen.
每次我出手  总是没什么好事儿
It's because you can't control it.
是因为你不能收放自如
It controls you.
你受制于自己的能力
That's why we're here, Alex. To start your training.
所以你需要训练  阿历克斯
What you're doing is incredible.
你的能力超乎寻常
You're hitting a pitch sound that at the same resonate frequency of the glass.
你的音调与玻璃的共振频率达到了一致
That's why it shatters.
所以它碎了
This is like any other muscle in the body.
声带无异于体内其他肌肉
You can control it.
你能控制自己发出的声音
"In each of us, two natures are at war."
"每个人都徘徊在善恶之间"
Robert Louis Stevenson, "Jekyll and Hyde".
罗伯特·路易斯·史蒂文森在"化身博士"中的独白
Top marks.
答对了
Still it really wasn't really about good and evil. Was it, Hank.
其实也不关善恶的事  对吧  汉克
It was about man's animal nature, and his struggle to control it.
讲得是人的兽性  和他抵抗兽性
To conform.
最终遵从兽性
It is that struggle which is holding you back.
就是这种摇摆不定束缚了你
Jekyll is afraid of what he could be capable of.
化身博士害怕自己的能力
You are too.
你也是一样
If you're serious about me doing this,
要是非要我在这儿练习
you might want to get back.
你最好找个地方先躲起来
- Of course, should I shut the door? - Yeah.
- 必须的  用不用关门  - 关上吧
Whenever you're ready.
准备好了就开始吧
My god.
我去
I will teach you to control this, Alex.
我会教你收放自如  阿历克斯
You're sure that this will work.
你确定这玩意能用吧
Anything is possible. I based the design...
一切皆有可能  这个设计是按照...
Hank, stop talking. Come on.
汉克  别聊了  快点
Now remember, scream as hard as you can.
记住  往死了喊
You need the sound waves to be supersonic.
想要超音速飞行就靠你自制音波了
Catch them at the right angle, and they should carry you.
对准角度的话  应该能飞起来
"They should carry me." That's reassuring.
"应该能飞起来"  还真让人安心
Good luck.
祝你好运
And don't forget to scream.
别忘了大声喊
If you want to beat me this time, you have to set the beast free.
这次要是想跑过我  得释放你的兽性
On your marks, get set...GO!
各就各位  预备...开始
Oh, congratulations, my friend.
祝贺你  哥们
Robert Louis Stevenson would have been proud.
罗伯特·路易斯·史蒂文森会为你自豪的
Impressive, Hank.
干得漂亮  汉克
Feet like those,
有那样的脚
all you need is a red nose.
再加个红鼻头就可以去拉雪橇了
Right, Bozo?
你说对吧  傻大个儿
I'm done here.
这儿没我的事儿了
Thank you, Alex
真会帮倒忙  阿历克斯
Come on, Hank.
过来  汉克
If you're using half the concentration to look normal.
如果你光顾着掩饰自己的不同
Then you're only half paying attention to whatever else you do.
就没办法做好该做的事了
Just pointing out something that could save your life.
只想给你些保命忠告
You want society to accept you.
你想要社会接受你
But you can't even accept yourself.
可你自己都不肯接受
Sexy.
帅气
This is just the prototype.
这还是半成品
The real will look considerably better, it'll be a whole suit.
成品是一整套  更有看头
See these sensors measure your energy output,
这些探测器能检测你发出能量的大小
this panel focuses it and the excess is absorbed.
这块嵌板能集中能量并将多余的吸收掉
All right try hitting the one in the middle,
好了  试试打中间那个靶子
just the one in the middle, mind.
就中间那个  小心点儿
Good luck.
祝你好运
You ought to see this.
快来看看
Your genes are extraordinary, you know that.
你的基因很特殊
Your cells age at half the rate of a normal human.
细胞老化速度是常人的一半
When you're forty you will still have the looks of a teenager.
等你四十岁了  还会是年轻人的模样
You have the most incredible cellular structure I've ever seen.
这是我见过的最非凡的细胞结构
You truly believe I'll fly this time?
你确定这回我飞得起来吗
Unreservedly.
确信无疑
- I trust you. - The task.
- 我相信你  - 先完成任务
- I don't trust him. - Say nothing.
- 我不相信他  - 你什么也别说
I'm going to die!
我要死了
All right, look, we're not going to
没事  要是不想做的话
make you do anything that your not so...
我们不会逼你的...
- Here, let me help him. - Erik!
- 过来  我来帮你  - 埃里克
What?
怎么了
You know you were thinking the same.
你不也是这么想的吗
Wonderful work Hank, thank you very much.
太棒了  汉克  非常感谢
All right, Alex, I want you to hit the X.
好了  阿历克斯  射中X
And try not to hit me, there's a good chap.
尽量别射我  好孩子
- You're serious? - I'm very serious.
- 玩真的吗  - 非常认真
I have complete and utter faith in you.
我对你绝对有信心
Am I still a Bozo?
现在还说我傻吗
Yes, Hank. You're still a Bozo.
对  汉克  你还是傻大个儿
But nice job.
但是衣服做得不错
See that?
看见那个没
Try turning it to face us.
试试把它转向我们
You know, I believe the true focus
我觉得关键在于
lies somewhere between rage and serenity.
愤怒与平静之间的某个点
Would you mind, if I...
介不介意我...
What did you just do to me?
你刚才把我怎么了
I accessed the brightest corner of your memory system.
我进入了你记忆系统里最光明的部分
It's a very beautiful memory, Erik, thank you.
真是美好的记忆  埃里克  谢谢你
I didn't know I still had that.
我都不知道自己还记得那些
There's so much more to you than you know.
还有很多你自己没察觉的记忆存在
Not just pain, and anger.
不光是痛苦和愤怒
There's good too, I felt it.
也有好的事物  我感觉到了
And when you can access all that.
等你能回忆起全部的时候
You will possess a power no one can match.
你就会所向披靡
Not even me.
无人能敌
So, come on. Try again.
所以再来  再试试
Well done.
干得好
The President is about to make his address.
总统演说马上要开始了
It shall be the policy of
国家政策上来讲
this nation to regard any nuclear missile,
任何越过古巴禁运线的
...crossing the embargo line, that surrounds Cuba,
核导弹行动
as an attack by the Soviet Union on the United States.
都应被视为苏联对美国发起的进攻
Requiring a full retaliatory response, upon the Soviet Union.
对此美方应予以全力反击
- That's where we're going to find, Shaw. - How do you know?
- 尚就在那里  - 你怎么知道
Two super powers facing off,
两个超级大国展开对峙
and he want's to start world war III.
而他想挑起第三次世界大战
He won't leave anything to chance.
他不会错过这个良机
So much for diplomacy.
外交话题到此为止
I suggest you all get a good nights sleep.
大家还是为明天做好准备吧
...ultimately leads to war.
...最终导致战争
Tensions mount as the Soviet Missile ship nears Cuba.
苏联船只靠近古巴使两国关系更加紧张
All diplomatic efforts to avert Nuclear war have thus far failed.
所有避免核战的外交尝试均以失败告终
As the American people ready themselves,
美方已做好准备
for the likelihood of an atomic attack.
迎接可能到来的原子突击
There are widespread reports of panic wide.
全国上下人心惶惶
Supermarkets cleared.
超市被抢售一空
As shelters unused since the second world war,
二战之后就未经使用过的避难所
are stocked for what may lie ahead.
到了派上用场的时刻
In all its history, American has never faced a greater threat.
美方遭遇到前所未有的巨大威胁
The world is primed for war. And there's no one to stop me.
战争就要降临  且没人能阻挡我
Come in.
进来
Got a surprise for you.
给你个惊喜
I isolated the right marker in your DNA sample.
我分离了你的DNA样本中相应的部分
The serum works like an anti-biotic.
这血清跟抗生素的原理一样
Attacking the cells that cause our physical mutation.
会攻击引发我们外表异变的细胞
It won't affect your abilities, just your appearance.
它只对你的外貌有效  不会影响能力
Do you still want to do this?
你还想变成普通人的样子吗
Should we have to hide?
我们一定要隐藏吗
You already do.
你已经藏起来了
You're hiding right now. Like I have my whole life.
此刻的你就像我一直那样  掩藏自己
I don't want to feel like a freak, all the time.
我不想一直像个怪物
- I just want to look... - ...normal.
- 我只想看起来...- 普通人
Yeah.
没错
Hank, don't.
汉克  不要改变自己
You're beautiful, Hank.
你很美  汉克
Everything you are, you're perfect.
你的一切都很美  你是完美的
Look at all of us. Look at all we've achieved this week.
看看我们大家  想想这星期的训练成果
All we will achieve.
还有我们将会达成的一切
We are different.
我们与众不同
But we shouldn't be trying to fit into society.
但是我们不该费力气去融入社会
Society should inspire and be more like us.
社会应该向我们靠拢
Mutant, and proud.
突变  自豪
It behooves me to tell you,
我应当告诉你
but even if we save the world tomorrow.
就算明天我们拯救了世界
And mutants are accepted into society.
变种人被社会接纳
My feet and your natural blue form.
我的脚和你的蓝皮肤
Will never be deemed beautiful.
永远不会被认为是美的
You look beautiful now.
现在你看上去很美
We need this cure.
我们需要这一针
Cuba,Russia,America,makes no difference.
古巴 俄罗斯 美国 没什么区别
Shaw's declared war on mankind, on all of us.
尚在向全人类宣战  向我们宣战
He has to be stopped.
必须阻止他
I'm not gonna stop Shaw.
我不准备阻止尚
I'm gonna kill him.
我要杀了他.
Do you have it into all of that ?
这步你想到了吗
You've known that all along why I was here, Charles.
我加入的目的你最清楚  查尔斯
But things have changed.
但事出有变
What started as a covert mission,
本来这是秘密任务
...tomorrow mankind will know that mutants exist.
但明天变种人将会为世人所知
Shaw, us... they won't differentiate.
尚和我们...在他们眼里没有区别
They'll fear us, and that fear will turn to hatred.
他们会惧怕我们  而恐惧会变成怨恨
Not if we stop a war. Not if we can prevent Shaw.
除非我们阻止战争  阻止尚
Not if we risk our lives doing so.
拼上我们的性命
Would they do the same for us?
他们会为我们出生入死吗
We have it in us to be the better man.
能力越大  责任越大
We already are.
我们做得够好了
We're the next stage of human evolution.
我们是人类进化的下一阶段
- You said it yourself. - Enough.
- 你自己都说过  - 够了
Are you really so naive
你真的幼稚到以为
as to think they won't battle their own extinction?
他们不会为自己的生存反击我们吧
- Or is it arrogance? - I'm sorry.
- 还是你太过自负了  - 你说什么
After tomorrow they're going to turn on us.
明天过后他们的矛头会转向我们
And you're blind to it,
而你却视而不见
because you believe they're all like Moira.
只因为你觉得他们都像莫伊洛一样
And you believe they're all like Shaw.
而你觉得他们都像尚一样
Listen to me, very carefully my friend.
仔细听我说  朋友
Killing Shaw will not bring you peace.
杀了尚不会让你得到安慰
Peace was never an option.
杀他并不是为了平复内心
No.
不要这样
Well...
那个...
This is a surprise.
吓我一跳
The nice kind?
不是惊吓吧
No, Raven, why don't you go to bed.
是惊喜  瑞雯  你怎么不睡觉
Maybe in a few years.
过几年再来勾引我吧
How about now?
现在不好吗
I prefer the real Raven.
我喜欢真实的你
I said the real, Raven.
我说的是  真实的你
Perfection.
完美绝伦
- Could you pass me my robe? - You don't have to hide.
- 把浴袍给我好吗  - 你不必隐藏
Have you ever looked at a tiger,
你以前看到老虎
and thought you'd want to cover it up?
会想要把它藏起来吗
No, but...
不会  可是...
You're an exquisite creature, Raven.
你完美无瑕  瑞雯
Only in life the world tries to tame you.
只是生活试图把你驯服
It's time for you to be free.
是你解放自己的时候了
You know sometimes I wonder what my life would have been like.
有时我想  如果那晚
If you hadn't found me here that night.
你没发现我的话  我的生活会是如何
Fairable, E..Gah...ah.
这个嘛
For gods sake, Raven!
天哪  瑞雯
Where are you clothes? Put some, put some clothes on.
你的衣服呢  快穿上
That's not what you said when you first saw me.
第一次见面时你可不是这么说的
But I guess pets are always cuter when they're little, right?
还是小时候比较可爱吧
Raven, I don't know what's got into you lately.
瑞雯  我不知道你最近是怎么了
I thought you'd be in a good mood.
我以为你心情挺好的
Hank tells me he's found the answer
汉克告诉我他能处理
to your cosmetic problem.
你外表的问题
You going to tell me what's the matter?
跟我谈谈是怎么回事儿
Or will I have to read your mind?
还是我得用上读心术
You promised me you would never do that.
你答应过不会对我用的
Until recently, I never had to
以前不用超能力
use my powers to know what you were thinking, Raven.
我也能知道你的想法  瑞雯
You know Charles, I used to think it was gonna be
查尔斯  我原以为你会跟我
you and me against the world.
一起对抗这个世界
And no matter how bad the world gets,
可是不管这个世界变得多糟
you don't want to be against it, do you?
你都不想与之抗衡  是不是
You want to be a part of it.
你想要成为它的一份子
What the hell happened here?
这里究竟发生什么了
Hank has been busy.
汉克没歇着
Do we really have to wear these?
我们真得穿成这样吗
As none of us has mutated to endure extreme G force,
既然我们忍受不了极度重力
or being riddled by bullets, I suggest we suit up.
也不能挡子弹  还是穿上比较保险
Where's Hank?
汉克哪儿去了
I'm here.
我在这儿
Hank?
汉克
It didn't attack the cells.
血清没有攻击那些细胞
It enhanced them.
反倒加强了它们
It didn't work.
没起作用
Yes, it did, Hank.
它起作用了  汉克
Don't you see? This is who you were meant to be.
没看出来吗  你就该这样
This is you.
这才是你
No more hiding.
别再隐藏了
Never looked better, man.
棒透了  哥们
Hank!
汉克
Don't mock me.
不许笑话我
Hank, put him down immediately, please.
汉克  立刻放他下来  别闹了
Hank...HANK!
汉克...汉克
I wasn't.
我说的实话
Even I got to admit, you look pretty bad ass.
我得说  你看上去确实像个大反角
I think I got a new name for you, Beast.
我给你想到个新名字  野兽
You sure you can fly this thing?
你确定能开飞机吗
Of course I can, I designed it.
废话  飞机是我造的
(古巴)
Status of the cargo ship?
货船状况如何
Bearing 1-8-0, 12 knots.
正对方向  十二海里位置
Three minutes to the embargo line, sir.
距抵达禁运线还有三分钟  长官
God help them if they cross it.
他们要是越线就自求多福吧
God help us all.
愿上帝保佑
Sound general quarters.
发起战斗警报
General quarters, general quarters.
战斗警报  战斗警报
- All hands man battle stations! - Yes, sir.
- 全体进入战备状态  - 是的  长官
Set condition zero.
待命准备
General quarters, battle stations.
战斗警报  战斗警报
Captain, we already have our orders.
船长  我们已经得到指令了
Why so eager for new ones?
为什么还盼着新的命令
I've lived through one war, comrade.
我经历过一场战争  同志
I'd prefer not to start another.
我不想再起争端
Battle stations, NOW!
立刻进入战备状态
Gun boss, target cargo ship, bearing 1-8-0.
炮手瞄准正前方货船
Fleet reports all weapons ready.
舰队报告  全部武装待命
From the Kremlin, sir.
克里姆林宫来的消息  长官
New orders. As of 1025 hours,
新指令  十点二十五分之前
the cargo vessel Aral sea, is hereby ordered to...
特命咸海号货船...
...reverse course and return to port in Odessa.
...改变航向返回敖德萨
Aral Sea, come in.
咸海号  请回答
They are not responding.
他们没有回复
She's not turning around.
船只没有掉头
Aral Sea, you are ordered to turn around.
咸海号  命令你原地返回
Do not cross the line.
不要越过警戒线
Target ready to be fired upon, sir.
目标已被瞄准  长官
- Stand by to fire. - Standing by, sir.
- 预备射击  - 待命  长官
Looks pretty messy out there.
那边看起来一团糟
Aral Sea, you are ordered to turn around.
咸海号  命令你原地返回
The crew of the Aral Sea are all dead. Shaw's been there.
咸海号船员全都死了  尚去过那里
He's still here, somewhere.
他还在
He's set the ship on course for the embargo line.
他把船驶向了禁航线
That ship crosses the line, our boys are going to blow it up.
这艘船只一旦过线  就会遭受我方轰炸
And the war begins.
战争就会开始
Unless they're not on board.
除非他们不在船上
USS Independence, this is, Alexander Nevski.
美方独立舰  我是亚历山大·诺维茨基
We have lost control of our cargo ship.
我们失去了对我方货船的控制
She's been instructed to stop. Do not fire.
已经命令它返航  不要开火
Repeat, do not fire.
重复  不要开火
They've signaled their cargo ship to turn around, sir.
苏军已要求己方货船返航  长官
It's a ruse, pay no attention. Stand by to fire.
这是诡计  不用理会  预备开火
- Standing by to fire, sir. - On my count.
- 预备开火  长官  - 听我倒数
Five...four...
五  四
Hold on! Hold on!
抓紧  抓紧
No!
不要
- What was that? - The Russians,
- 怎么回事  - 那些苏联人
they have fired on their own ship.
他们向自己的船开火
A little warning next time, professor.
下次提前打个招呼  教授
Sorry about that.
对不起啊
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 你没事吧  - 还好
Son of a...
搞什么
Give me Sinclar on the horn, I want a new set of orders.
让辛克莱接电话  我要一套新的部署
Congratulations, comrade.
恭喜你  同志
You just averted a Nuclear war.
你刚刚让我们避免了一场核战争
What?
什么
Take him to the brig.
把他带到禁闭室
What? What just happened?
什么  发生了什么
They say the comrade lost his mind.
他们说那个人失去意识了
The Americans' are plotting.
美国人耍花招
They're here.
他们来了
That telepath is powerful.
心灵感应很强烈了
We're moving to a back-up plan.
我们开始后备计划
- That was inspired, Charles. - Thank you very much.
- 太振奋人心了  查尔斯  - 谢谢
But I still can't locate Shaw.
但我仍然无法定位尚
He's down there, we need to find him now.
他就在下面  我们现在就要找到他
Hank?
汉克
- Is there anything unusual on the radar scanners? - No, nothing.
- 雷达上显示什么异常了吗  - 没有
Well then he must be under water.
那他一定在水下
And obviously we don't have Sonar.
很显然我们没有声纳
Yes we do.
不  我们有
我们有
They were ready for war.
他们为战争做好准备了
We just need to strike another match to light the fuse.
我们只需要用另一根火柴点燃导火线
And we still have the most powerful weapon of all.
我们仍会有世上最强大的武器
Me.
那就是我
Turn the nuclear reactor to
我吸收核反应堆100%的能量输出
100% output and make sure I'm not disturbed.
这之间我不能被打扰
Hank, level the bloody plane!
汉克  把这该死的飞机拉平
Whoa, you back right off.
你也要来
Beast, open the Bombay doors.
野兽  把底仓门打开
Remember, this is a muscle. You control it.
记住  这只是块肌肉  你能控制它
You'll be in here the entire time. We'll see you soon.
就这么想  我们一会儿见
On my mark. 3, 2, 1 GO!
听我命令  3  2  1  走
Alert the fleet, they may want to take their cams off.
警告舰队  他们想把他们的监控摘下来
Banshee's got a location on Shaw.
海妖发现尚的位置了
You ready for this?
准备好了吗
Let's find out.
我们去找他吧
(反应堆能量指示)
Remember, the point between rage and serenity.
记住  关键在于愤怒与平静之间的某个点
Erik, take my hand!
埃里克  抓着我的手
Hold on guys, it's going to get bumpy.
抓紧了伙计们  要开始颠簸了
Erik, take my hand!
埃里克  抓着我的手
Down.
下来
- Moira, Moira, are you all right? - Yeah, I'm okay.
- 莫伊洛  你还好吧  - 没事
I read the teleporter's mind.
我进入了守门人的思想
Shaw's drawing all of the power out of his sub.
尚正在抽取潜水艇中所有的能量
He's turning himself into some kind of nuclear bomb.
他要把自己变成一枚核弹
We've got no time, the Geiger counter's going out of control.
我们没时间了  盖革计数器快超量程了
All right Moira, this is what we're going to do.
好的莫伊洛  接下来我们
Get on the radio and send both fleet's out immediately.
用步话机通知双方的舰队迅速撤离
I'm going in.
我要进去了
Beast, Havok, back him up.
野兽  蹂躏者  掩护他
Erik, I can guide you through once you're in.
埃里克  你进去后听我指示
But I need you to shut down whatever it is that's blocking me.
不过你要扫清阻碍我的障碍
Then we just hope to god it's not to late for me to stop him.
剩下就只能祈祷为时不晚
- Got it. - Good luck!
- 搞定  - 祝你好运
- Raven, stop! - I'm going out there.
- 瑞雯  停下  - 我要出去
We don't have time for this.
没时间玩这个
Anything comes in that entrance, you're taking care of it, ok?
你看着门口  以防外人进去
Fine.
好吧
Beast!
野兽
If we go, you go
大不了同归于尽
We believe Shaw is trying to detonate some kind of bomb.
我们认为尚正试着引爆一种炸弹
Erik, make for the middle of the vessel.
埃里克  到船的中间去
That's the point my mind can't penetrate.
那里我的思想无法进入
We have to assume that, that's where Shaw is.
我们假设尚就在那里
Gang way, gang way.
不许动  不许动
That's the nuclear reactor. Disable it.
那是核反应堆  破坏它
Stop, don't move.
住手  不要动
Get down!
蹲下
Erik you're there, you've reached the void.
埃里克你到了中部  那里没人
He's not here Charles, Shaw is not here.
他不在这里  查尔斯  尚不在这里
- He's left the sub. - What? He's got to be there.
- 他离开潜艇了  - 什么  他肯定在
He has to be, there's no where else he can be, keep looking.
他一定在  不会去别的地方  再找找
And I'm telling you he's not, there's no one here, god damn it!
我说了他不在  这里没人  该死
Erik, what a pleasant surprise.
埃里克  真是个惊喜啊
Erik? Erik!
埃里克  埃里克
So good to see you again.
再次见到你真好
May I ask you something?
我能问你些问题吗
Why are you on their side?
你为什么在他们那边
- He's gone. - What?
- 他消失了  - 什么
He's gone into the void. I can't communicate with him there.
他进入盲区了  我联系不到他
Why fight for a doomed race who will hunt us down,
为什么要为即将灭亡的种族战斗
...as soon as they realize their reign
人类一旦发现气数已尽
is coming to an end.
就会将我们赶尽杀绝
I'm sorry for what happened in the camps.
我对军营里发生事道歉
I truly am.
我是真心的
He's back.
又找到他了
Erik, whatever you're doing keep doing it, it's starting to work.
埃里克  继续  起作用了
But everything I did, I did for you.
但我做的每一件事都是为了你
To unlock your power. To make you embrace it.
开启并让你拥有超能力
It's working.
很有效
I'm starting to see him, but I can't yet touch his mind.
我能看到他了  但我不能看到他的思想
You've come a long way from bending gates.
从弯曲的铁门  你一路走来
I'm so proud of you.
我为你感到骄傲
And you're just starting to scratch the surface.
你还要走很长的路
Think how much further we could go, together.
想想我们能一起走多远
Stop, Azazel!
住手  阿撒佐恶魔
I don't want to hurt you, Erik. I never did.
我不想伤害你  埃里克  我从没有过
I want to help you.
我想帮助你
This is our time. Our age.
这是我们的时刻  我们的时代
We are the future of the human race.
我们是人类的未来
You and me, son. This world could be ours.
你和我  孩子  这世界是我们的
Everything you did, made me stronger.
你做的每件事  都使我更坚强
Made me the weapon I am today.
把我变成今天强大的我
That's the truth.
说的没错
I've known it all along.
我一直都明白
You are my creator.
你是我的造物主
NOW, Charles!
就是现在  查尔斯
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Moira be quiet, I can only control this man for so long.
莫伊洛安静点  我只能控制这家伙一会
Sorry, Charles.
对不起  查尔斯
Erik please, be the better man. You have it in...
埃里克  做个好人  你已经...
But I don't trust you.
可我不相信你
Erik, there will be no telling that...
埃里克  这样没法知道...
No.
不
- Charles? - Don't do this, Erik!
- 查尔斯  - 别这么做  埃里克
If you're in there, I'd like you to know that
如果你能听到  我希望你知道
I agree with every word you've said.
我同意你说的每一句话
We are the future.
我们是未来
But...
但是
...unfortunately, you killed my mother.
很不幸  你杀了我妈妈
This is what we're going to do.
接下来我把硬币还给你
No, please Erik, no.
不要  埃里克  别
I'm going to count to three. And I'm going to move the coin.
我数到三  我就要移动这枚硬币
One...
一
Please, Erik.
求你了  埃里克
Two...
二
Three.
三
The Russians share our concerns.
苏联和我们想法一致
And will join a strike on all the mutants.
联合向变种人发动袭击
We can end this threat for good.
我们就能永远结束这种威胁
We'll never have another opportunity like this.
良机不可错过
We have an agent on that beach.
我们有个特工还在海滩上
- One agent. - She's a good agent.
- 一个特工  - 她是个优秀的特工
She's collateral damage.
她是附带损害
Today our fighting stops.
今天我们的斗争结束了
Take off your blinders, brothers and sisters.
看看清楚吧  兄弟姐妹们
The real enemy is out there.
真正的敌人在那里
I feel their guns moving in the water.
我感到他们的枪在水中移动
Their metal targeting us.
他们的大炮瞄准我们
Americans, Soviets, humans.
美国人  苏联人  全人类
United in their fear of the unknown.
因为他们对未知的恐惧联合起来
A Neanderthal is running scared, my fellow mutants.
尼安得特人害怕了  我的变异同胞们
Go ahead, Charles.
继续  查尔斯
Tell me I'm wrong.
告诉我我错了
Fleet commander this is X-ray Bravo-70.
舰队指挥官  我是XB70小组
Respond, over.
请回答  结束
The beach is secure, call off the attack.
海滩安全  请求取消攻击
The beach is targeted and ready to be fired upon, sir.
瞄准就位  预备射击  长官
- Stand by. - Standing by, sir.
- 待命  - 待命  长官
Hello? Hello!
喂  喂
Fire. Fire.
开火  开火
Erik, you said yourself, we're the better men.
埃里克你说过我们都是更好的人
This is the time to prove it.
现在是证明它的时候了
There are thousands of men on those ships.
那些船上有上千个人
getting orders, innocent men.
只是服从命令  无辜的人
They're just following orders.
他们只是服从命令
I've been at the mercy of men just following orders.
我曾经对服从命令的人仁慈过
Never again.
不会再有第二次了
Erik Release them !
埃里克 放了他们
Noooooooo
不
I don't want to hurt you,don't make me.
我可不想伤害你 别逼我
Stay back !
别过来!
Erik, stop!
埃里克  住手
Gentlemen, it's been an honor serving with you.
先生们  和你们共事很骄傲
I'm so sorry.
对不起
I said back off!
我说了往后退
You, you did this!
是你  你干的
Please...
求你
She didn't do this, Erik. You did.
不是她  埃里克  是你干的
Us turning on each other, it's what they want.
他们想要我们反目成仇
I tried to warn you, Charles.
我警告过你  查尔斯
I want you by my side. We're brothers, you and I.
我想你在我这一边  你我是兄弟
All of us, together. Protecting each other.
我们所有人在一起  彼此保护
We want the same thing.
兄弟齐心
Oh, my friend.
我的朋友
I'm sorry, but we do not.
很抱歉  我们不是
Charles, I'm sorry, I'm so sorry, Charles.
查尔斯  我很抱歉  真的抱歉
It's all right, it's all right.
没关系  没关系
His society won't accept us.
他的社会不接纳我们
We form our own.
我们组建个社会吧
The humans has played their hand.
人类耍花招
Now we get ready to play ours.
我们奉陪
Who's with me?
谁和我一起
No more hiding.
不要再隐藏了
You, you should go with him. It's what you want.
你应该和他走  那才是你想要的
You promised me you would never read my mind.
你答应过我绝不读我的思想的
I know.
我知道
I promised you a great many things, I'm afraid.
我答应过你很多事  恐怕
I'm sorry.
对不起
Take care of him.
好好照顾他
And Beast, never forget.
野兽  别忘了
Mutant and proud.
变异  骄傲
Help me out, help him.
帮帮我  扶住他
I'm going to get you to a hospital.
我要把你送到医院
Wait, don't, Charles, don't move, okay.
等等  查尔斯  别动  好吗
All right, actually I ca.....I...I...
好吧  实际上  我
I can't feel my legs
我感觉不到我的腿了
I can't feel my legs.
In this week of Thanksgiving.
在这个感恩节
There is much for which we can be grateful.
我们有许多需要感激的东西
As you look back to where we stood, only four weeks ago.
回顾过去这四个星期我们的处境
The unity of this hemisphere, the support of our allies.
北半球的联合  盟友的支持
And the calm determination of the American people.
还有美国人民冷静的判断
These qualities may be tested many more times.
这些品质在近十年内
In this decade.
多次被检验
So how many students do you think you'll have here?
你说这里一旦开始办学校
Once you get the academy up and running.
你会有多少学生呢
As many as I can manage. Possibly more.
我能管住就行  最好更多
You know, one day the government
要知道  终于一天政府会
is going to realize how lucky they were,
意识到他们有多幸运
..To have Professor X on their side.
X教授站在他们这边
Yeah
是啊
It has been on the road to a professor now, aren't I.
我要去当教授了  对吧
First thing I'll be going bald.
首先我会变成光头
We're still on the government's side, Moira.
我们仍站在政府那边  莫伊洛
We're still a G-man, just without the G.
我们仍然是政府的人  只是没有名号
No, you're your own team now.
不  你们有自己的队伍
It's better.
这更好
You're, "X-Men".
你是X战警
Yes, I like the sound of that.
是啊  听上去不错
Moira, for us anonymity will be the first line of defense.
莫伊洛  隐姓埋名是我们第一道防线
I know.
我知道
They can threaten me all they want, Charles.
查尔斯  他们什么时候威胁我
I'll never tell them where you are.
我都不会告诉他们你在哪的
Ever.
绝不
I know you won't.
我知道你不会
My love.
亲爱的
I remember the attack on HQ.
我记得那次袭击
Leaving to go somewhere else.
之后去了一个地方
And then this morning, I woke up at home.
再然后今早上  我在家醒了
That's it.
就是这样
All that time wiped clean from your mind.
那些记忆全从你大脑里清除了
Just gone.
消失了
He can do that. You don't remember anything?
他能这么做  你什么都不记得了吗
Sometimes I get fragments.
偶尔闪现一些片段
Like trees, sunlight.
比如大树  阳光
- A kiss. - Aw, Jesus.
- 一个吻  - 哦上帝
Gentlemen, this is why the CIA is no place for a woman.
先生们  这就是为什么中情局不要女性
What the hell was that?
那边怎么回事
I know we've had our differences.
我知道我们之间有分歧
- Where's your telepath friend? - Gone.
- 你心灵感应的朋友呢  - 走了
Left a bit of a gap in my life. If I'm to be honest.
老实说  在我在心里留了一道坎
I was rather hoping you would fill it.
希望你能填平它
Join us.
加入我们吧
Erik, I believe.
你是埃里克吧
I prefer...
我更喜欢被称为
Magneto.
万磁王